Finding Aid for the Alex North Motion Picture Music PASC-M.0017
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Somebody killed her husband
  - North, Alex. King Wenceslas. Score and parts. Reel - 2 part - 1. Copy of score, onion skins [2 leaves], and parts. Flt -1, trpt -1, pno - 2, perc - 2, bass - 1. (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - North, Alex. Jenny and Jerry. Score and parts. Reel 2 - part 2. Copy of score, onion skins [2 leaves], and parts. Flts - 2, clars - 3, bassoon - 1, vlns - 4, vla - 1, cello - 1, fender bass - 1, bass - 1, perc - 2, pno - 2, harp - 1. (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - North, Alex. Caribbean Report. Score and parts. Reel 2 - part 3. Copy of score, onion skins [7 leaves], and parts. Flt - 1, trpt - 1, gtr/bass - 2, pno - 2, drums/perc - 2. (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - North, Alex. Kristine. Score and parts. Reel 2 - part 4. Copy of score, onion skins [3 leaves], and parts. woodwind - 1, trpt - 1, pno - 3, gtr - 1, drums - 1. (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - North, Alex. I love you. Score and parts. Reel 3 - part 1. copy of score, onion skins [2 leaves], and parts. Flts - 1, clars - 1, trpt - 1, vlns - 4, vla - 1, cello - 1, bass - 1, pno - 2, perc - 2. (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - North, Alex. Why me? Score and parts. Reel 3 - part 3/reel 4 - part 1. Copy of score [2], onion skins [10 leaves], and parts. Flts - 3, clars - 2, oboe - 1, bsn - 1, hrn - 2, vlns - 4, vla - 1, cello - 1, bass - 1, pno - 4, harp - 1, perc - 4. (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - North, Alex. First down. Score and parts. Reel 4 - part 2. Copy of score, onion skins [3 leaves], and parts. Flts - 2, oboe - 1, clars - 3, bsn - 1, hns - 3, gtr - 1, vlns - 4, vla - 1, cello - 1, bass - 1, fender bass - 1, perc - 3, pno - 3, harp - 1. (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - North, Alex. Dead husband. Score and parts. Reel 5 - part 1. Copy of score, onion skins [7 leaves], and parts. Flts - 2, clasr - 2, bsn - 1, vlns- 4, vla - 1, cello - 1, bass - 1, pno - 3, perc - 3, harp - 1. (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - North, Alex. Flora. Score and parts. Reel 5 - part 2. Copy of score, onion skins [3 leaves], and parts. Flts - 3, oboe - 1, clars - 2, hns - 3, trpts - 1, trbs - 2, vlns - 4, vla - 1, cello - 1, bass - 1, pno - 3, perc - 3. (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - North, Alex. Danziger. Score and parts. Reel 6 - part 1. Copy of score [2], onion skins [9 leaves], and parts. Flts - 3, oboe - 1, clars - 2, bsn - 1, hns - 3, tuba - 1, vlns - 4, vla - 1, cello - 1, bass - 2, pno - 3, perc - 7. (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - North, Alex. Love and Benjamin. Score and parts. Reel 8 - part 2. Copy of score, onion skins [8 leaves], and parts. Flts - 3, oboe - 1, clars - 2, bassoon - 1, hns - 3, vlns - 4, vla - 1, cello - 1, bass - - 1, gtr - 1, pno - 4, harp - 1, perc - 5. (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - North, Alex. Love at last. Score and parts. Reel 8 - part 2 alt. Copy of score, onion skins [1 leave], and parts. Flts - 1, hns - 1, gtr - 1, vlns - 4, vla - 1, cello - 1, bass - 1, fender rhodes [1 leave manuscript], perc - 1. (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - North, Alex. Disguise. Score and parts. Reel 9 - part 1. Copy of score, onion skins [15 leaves], and parts. Flts - 3, oboes - 1, clars - 2, bsn - 1, hns - 3, trpts - 2, trbs - 2, tuba - 1, vlns - 4, vla - 1, cello - 1, bass - 2, pno - 3, gtr - 1, harp - 1, perc - 3. (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - North, Alex. Beret. Score and parts. Reel 9 - part 2. Copy of score [2], onion skins [5 leaves], and parts. Clars - 2, bsn - 1, hns - 3, vlns - 4, vla - 1, cello & bass - 2, pno - 3, harp - 1, perc - 1. (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - North, Alex. Herbet. Score and parts. Reel 9 - part 3. Copy of score, onion skins [2 leaves], and parts. Flts - 3, bsn - 1, trbs - 2, vlns - 4, vla - 1, cello - 1, bass - 1, harp - 1, pno - 3, perc - 4. (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - North, Alex. Chase #1. Score and parts. Reel 11 - part 1. Copy of score, onion skins [12 leaves]. and parts. Flts - 3, oboe - 1, clars - 2, bassoon - 1, hns - 3, trpts - 2, trbs - 2, tuba - 1, vlns - 3, vla - 1, cello - 1, bass - 1, pno - 6, perc - 8. (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - North, Alex. Chase #2. Score and parts. Reel 11 - part 2. Copy of score, onion skins [21 leaves], and parts. Flts - 3, oboe - 1, clars - 2, bsn - 1, hns - 2, trpts - 2, trbs - 2, tuba - 1, vlns - 3, vla - 1, cello - 1, gtr - 1, harp - 1, bass - 1, pno - 3, perc - 5. (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - North, Alex. Closing theme / end credits. Score and parts. Reel 11 - part 3. Copy of score, onion skins [10 leaves], and parts. Flts - 3, oboe - 1, clars - 2, bsn - 1, hns - 3, trpts - 2, trbs - 2, tuba - 1, vlns - 4, vla - 1, cello - 1, bass - 1, gtr - 1, pno - 3, perc - 4. (Box 83, Folder 2)
- South Seas
  - North, Alex. Manuscripts and parts. Conductor's score and parts. (Box 13, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 14, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 15, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 16, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 17, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 18, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 19, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 20, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 21, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 22, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 23, Folder unknown container)
- Spartacus, [1960]
  - North, Alex. [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score] (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Main Title, 4 [1-4] (Othertype ____)
    - The Mines, 8 [5-12] (Othertype 2 A)
    - Caravan, 3 [13-15] (Othertype 2 B)
    - Varinia's Theme, 5 [16-20] (Othertype 3 A)
    - unspecified (Othertype 3 AX)
    - unspecified (Othertype 3 B)
    - Spartacus Love Theme, 8 [21-27] (Othertype _____)
    - Eduardo, 5 [28-32] (Othertype 4 A)
    - Painting, 3 [33-35] (Othertype 4 B)
    - Spartacus Cell, 1 [36] (Othertype 4 C)
    - Kitchen #1, 3 [37-39] (Othertype 4 D)
    - Kitchen #2, 2 [40-41] (Othertype 4 F, Othertype 5 A)
    - Crassus, 1 [42] (Othertype 5 B)
    - Pre-flight, 4 [43-47] (Othertype 6 B)
    - Draba Fight, 14 [48-61] (Othertype 6 C)
    - [no title], 3 [62-64] (Othertype 7 A)
    - Kill, 2 [65-66] (Othertype 7 AA)
    - Draba's Body, 5 [67-71] (Othertype 7 B)
    - Revolt, 10 [72-81] (Othertype 7 C)
  - North, Alex. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Breakout, 17 [82-98] (Othertype 8 AA)
    - Slaves Escape, 3 [99-101] (Othertype 8 A)
    - Crassus Home, 10 [102-111] (Othertype 9 A)
    - Deserted School, 4 [112-115] (Othertype 10 A)
    - Forest Meeting, 13 [116-128] (Othertype 11 A)
    - Source Music #1, 2 [129-130] (Othertype ______)
    - Vesuvius Camp, 9 [131-139] (Othertype 12 B)
    - New recruits, 4 [140-143] (Othertype 12 C, Othertype 13 A)
    - Glabrus March #1, 1 [144] (Othertype 13 B)
    - Vesuvius Montage, 6 [145-150] (Othertype 13 C)
    - Love Sequence, 5 [151-155] (Othertype 13 E)
    - Glabrus March #2, 1 [156] (Othertype 14 A)
    - End of Entre-acte Music, 1 [157] (Othertype 14 A, Othertype 15 A-B)
    - Glabrus defeated, 14 [158-171] (Othertype 14 B, Othertype 15 A)
    - Glabrus disgraced, 4 [172-175] (Othertype 15 C-D)
    - Off to the sea, 8 [176-183] (Othertype 15 X)
    - On to the sea, 6 [184-189] (Othertype 16 A)
    - Luceria Camp, 2 [190-191] (Othertype 16 B)
    - Beside the pool, 4 [192-195] (Othertype 16 C, Othertype 17 AA)
    - Sound the trumpets, 2 [196-197] (Othertype 17)
    - Metapontum Triumph, 5 [198-202] (Othertype 17 B)
    - Opening bridge, 6 [203-208] (Othertype 17 B)
    - Roman Baths, 10 [209-218] (Othertype 17 C, Othertype 18 AA)
  - North, Alex. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Arrival at the Beach, 3 [219-221] (Othertype 18 A)
    - Intermission Title Music, 1 [222] (Othertype 18 A)
    - Festival, 9 [223-231] (Othertype 18 B)
    - Dance added for 18 C, 2 [232-233] (Othertype 18 C)
    - Sound the trumpets, 1 [234] (Othertype 18 D)
    - Back from the sea, 2 [235-236] (Othertype 19 D)
    - Crassus Camp, 3 [237-239] (Othertype 19 E)
    - Camp at night, 4 [240-243] (Othertype 20 A)
    - Expectant Parents, 6 [242-247] (Othertype 21 A)
    - Crassus Mental Effect, 1 [248] (Othertype ______)
    - Manoeuvres, 22 [249-260] (Othertype 21 B)
    - Formations, 5 [261-265] (Othertype 21 C, Othertype 22 AA)
    - The Battle, 16 [266-281] (Othertype 22 A)
  - North, Alex. (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - I am Spartacus, 4 [282-285] (Othertype 22 C, Othertype 23 A)
    - Crucifixion March, 2 [286 -287] (Othertype 24 A)
    - Varina & Crassus, 7 [295-301] (Othertype 24 B)
    - Fear of death, 4 [302-305] (Othertype 24 C, Othertype 25 A)
    - Spartacus defies Crassus, 4 [306-309] (Othertype 25 B)
    - The Last Fight, 23 [310-332] (Othertype 25 C, Othertype 26 A)
    - Final farewell and end title, 15 [323-337] (Othertype 26 B)
- Stagestruck, [1958]
  - North, Alex. (75 leaves) [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score] (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Main title, 17 [1-17] (Othertype _____)
    - Introducing Eva, 3 [18-20] (Othertype 1)
    - Eva and Hedges, 3 [21-23] (Othertype 2 1)
    - Joe reads review, 6 [24-29] (Othertype 3)
    - Eva's Balcony, 1 [30] (Othertype 4)
    - Eva's Balcony, Part 2, 5 [31-35] (Othertype 5 1)
    - Remorse, 5 [36-40] (Othertype 5 2)
    - Only man is vile, 1 [41] (Othertype 6 1)
    - Recitation #1 and #2, 3 [42-44] (Othertype 6 2)
    - Spanish Number, 3 [45-47] (Othertype 6 3)
    - First Italian Number, 1 [48] (Othertype 6 4)
    - Minetta Lane (Pt. 1), 3 [49-51] (Othertype 6 5)
    - New, 2 [52-53] (Othertype 6 8)
    - Minetta Lane (Part 2), 2 [54-55] (Othertype 7 1)
    - Secret Rehearsal, 5 [56-60] (Othertype 7 2)
    - First & Second Acts, 3 [61-63] (Othertype 9 2)
    - Thank you kiss, 9 [67-75] (Othertype 10 1)
- A Streetcar Named Desire [Warner Brothers, 1951]
  - North, Alex. (94 leaves) [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score] (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Main title, 2 [1-2] (Othertype ____)
    - [no title], 2 [3-4] (Othertype 5 3)
    - [no title], 3 [5-7] (Othertype 6 1)
    - [no title], 9 [8-17] (Othertype 7 1)
    - Collector Scene, 10 [17-26] (Othertype 7 2)
    - Pavillion Scene, 10 [27-36] (Othertype 8 2)
    - [no title], 3 [37-39] (Othertype 9 1)
    - [no title], 4 [40-43] (Othertype 9 2, Othertype 10 1)
    - [no title], 4 [44-47] (Othertype 10 1A)
    - [no title], 3 [48-50] (Othertype 10 2)
    - [no title], 2 [51-52] (Othertype 10 3)
    - [no title], 9 [53-61] (Othertype 11 1)
    - [no title], 8 [62-69] (Othertype 11 2)
    - [no title], 4 [70-73] (Othertype 12 1, Othertype 12 6)
    - [no title], 8 [74-81] (Othertype 13 1)
    - [no title], 5 [82-86] (Othertype 13 2)
    - [no title], 3 [87-89] (Othertype 14 1)
    - [no title], 5 [90-94] (Othertype 14 2)
- The Thirteenth Letter [20th Century-Fox, 1951]
  - North, Alex. (86 leaves) [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score] (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Main Title, 4 [1-4] (Othertype ____)
    - Scarlet Pen, 8 [5-12] (Othertype 1 2)
    - Scarlet Pen, 2 [13-14] (Othertype 1 4)
    - Scarlet Pen, 3 [15-17] (Othertype 2 1A)
    - Scarlet Pen, 5 [18-22] (Othertype 2 1)
    - Scarlet Pen, 2 [23-24] (Othertype 2 2)
    - Scarlet Pen, 3 [25-27] (Othertype 2 3, Othertype 3 1)
    - Scarlet Pen, 4 [28-31] (Othertype 3 2, Othertype 4 1)
    - Scarlet Pen, 1 [32] (Othertype 4 2)
    - [no title], 1 [33] (Othertype 4 4A)
    - [no title], 3 [34-36] (Othertype 4 4B)
    - Scarlet Pen, 4 [37-40] (Othertype 5 3)
    - Mayor's Speech, 4 [41-44] (Othertype 5 4)
    - Country, 2 [45-46] (Othertype 6 1)
    - Ferry-Love, 5 [47-51] (Othertype 6 2)
    - Going to church, 3 [52-54] (Othertype 6 3-3A)
    - Scarlet Pen, 1 [55] (Othertype 7 1)
    - Scarlet Pen, 4 [56- 59] (Othertype 8 1)
    - Scarlet Pen, 3 [60-62] (Othertype 8 1A)
    - Scarlet Pen-Denise-Cora, 5 [63-67] (Othertype 8 2)
    - Scarlet Pen-Cora-Pierson-Hospital, 9 [68-76] (Othertype 10 1)
    - Scarlet Pen, 5 [77-81] (Othertype 10 2)
    - Scarlet Pen-Country, 6 [82-86] (Othertype 10 3)
    - House
- Unchained [Warner Brothers, 1955]
  - North, Alex. (74 leaves) [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score, unless otherwise noted] (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - First meeting Mary & David, 4 [1-4] (ozalid copy) (Othertype ____)
    - Lonely Rivers Flow, 4 [5-8]
    - Main Title, 9 [9-17] (Othertype 1 1)
    - Scudder Fence, 12 [18-29] (Othertype 1 2)
    - Scudder Fence, 3 [30-32] (Othertype 1 2)
    - Scudder Mary, 5 [33-37] (Othertype 2 4)
    - Scudder Mary, 3 [38-40] (Othertype 2 4)
    - Scudder Garrity at Cell, 5 [41-45] (Othertype 3 1, Othertype 3 2)
    - Collection-Credo, 2 [46-47] (Othertype 4 1)
    - Library, 11 [48-58] (Othertype 5 1)
    - Montage-Garrity, 4 [59-62] (Othertype 6 2)
    - Howard Haskins, 4 [63-66] (Othertype 8 1)
    - Howard lessens Davitt's Bitterness, 2 [67-68] (Othertype 9 1)
    - Elaine walks out, 2 [69-70] (Othertype 10 1)
    - Escape, 4 [71-74] (Othertype 10 2)
- Viva Zapata [20th Century-Fox, 1952]
  - North, Alex. (78 leaves) [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score] (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Matiacas, 8 [1-8] (Othertype _____)
    - Forward, 1 [9] (Othertype 1 1X)
    - Main Title, 12 [10-21] (Othertype _____)
    - Diaz, 1 [22] (Othertype 1 2)
    - Zapata!, 4 [23-26] (Othertype 1 4)
    - Zapata's Love &, 5 [27-31] (Othertype 3 2)
    - Childrens Episode
    - Innocente's Death, 4 [32-35] (Othertype 4 1)
    - Gathering Forces, 5 [36-40] (Othertype 4 5)
    - Release, 1 [41] (Othertype 5 2)
    - Zapata walks, 11 [42-52] (Othertype 9 2)
    - Pablo, 4 [53-56] (Othertype 10 1)
    - Conscience, 2 [57-58] (Othertype 10 2)
    - Morelos, 3 [59-61] (Othertype 11 1)
    - Eufemio, 5 [62-66] (Othertype 11 2, Othertype 12 1)
    - Joseffa's Love, 5 [67-71] (Othertype 12 2)
    - Josepha, 2 [72-73] (Othertype 13 1)
    - Let no tyrant, 2 [74-75] (Othertype ____)
    - End Title End cast, 3 [76-78] (Othertype ____)
- Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf [Warner Brothers, 1966]
  - North, Alex. (50 leaves) Holograph, in pencil, of musical score (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Mishegaas, 2 [1-2] (Othertype 1 1)
    - Who's afraid of Virginia Woolf?, 2 [3-4] (Othertype ____)
    - Theme, solo piano version, 2 [5-6] (Othertype ___)
    - Colloquy, 7 [7-13] (Othertype 5 1)
    - Bergin, 7 [14-20] (Othertype 6 1)
    - Total War, 4 [21-24] (Othertype 9 1)
    - Snap, 3 [25-27] (Othertype 9 A)
    - Martha, 5 [28-32] (Othertype 10 1)
    - Sad, sad, sad, 5 [33-37] (Othertype 11 1)
    - Fleece, 6 [38-43] (Othertype 12 1)
    - Party's Over, 7 [44-50] (Othertype 13 1)
- Wise Blood
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 27, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 28, Folder unknown container)
- The Wonderful Country [United Artists, 1959]
  - North, Alex. (119 leaves) [Holograph, in pencil, of musical score, unless otherwise noted] (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - Main Title, 11 [1-11] (Othertype _____)
    - Into Puerto, 7 [12-18] (Othertype 1 2)
    - Brady's Leg, 2 [19-20] (Othertype 1 3, Othertype 2 1)
    - Sterners Pesos, 7 [21-26] (ozalid copy) (Othertype 2 2)
    - Homesick, 5 [27-31] (Othertype 3 1)
    - Ellen, 3 [32-34] (Othertype 3 3, Othertype 4 1)
    - Gringo, 3 [35-37] (Othertype 4 2)
    - Where did you get that hat?, 3 [38-41] (ozalid copy) (Othertype 5 1)
    - Polka, 3 [42-44] (Othertype 5 2)
    - Waltz, 2 [45-46] (Othertype 6 1)
    - Tears, 2 [47-48] (Othertype 6 2)
    - Escape, 6 [49-53] (Othertype 6 3)
    - Valdepenas, 3 [54-56] (Othertype 7 1)
    - Capitol City, 4 [57-60] (Othertype 7 3)
    - Mexican Traditional, 1 [61] (Othertype 8 1)
    - Fiesta, 6 [62-67] (Othertype 8 2)
    - Half a man, 3 [68-70] (Othertype 9 2)
    - Brady's Mission, 3 [71-73] (Othertype 9 3)
    - Chase, 7 [74-80] (Othertype 10 1)
    - Apaches, 7 [81-87] (Othertype 11 1)
    - The Trek, 6 [88-93] (Othertype 11 2)
    - Indian Fight, 7 [94-106] (Othertype 12 1)
    - Brady & Ellen, 5 [107-111] (Othertype 12 2)
    - Ellen & Brady cont'd, 2 [112-113] (Othertype 13 1)
    - End Title, 6 [114-119] (Othertype 13 4)
- 2001, A Space Odyssey [MGM, 1968]
  - North, Alex. (115 leaves) [Holograph, in pencil and ink, of musical score] (Box 12, Folder 48)
    - The Foraging, 5 [1-5] (Othertype 2 1)
    - Alternative version, 1 [6] (Othertype 2 1)
    - The Bluff, 5 [7-11] (Othertype 2 2)
    - Night Terrors, 3 [12-14] (Othertype 2 3)
    - The Bluff, 8 [15-22] (Othertype 2 3-4)
    - Bones, 3 [23-25] (Othertype 3 1)
    - Eat meat and kill, 16 [26-41] (Othertype 3 2)
    - Conclusion, 1 [42] (Othertype 3 2)
    - Space station, 11 [43-53] (Othertype 3 3)
    - rocking (Othertype 4 1)
    - Revised Version, 11 [54-64] (Othertype 3 3, Othertype 4 1)
    - Space station rocking, 4 [65-68] (Othertype 4 1)
    - End, 2 [69-70] (Othertype 4 1A)
    - Space talk, 10 [71-80] (Othertype 4 2)
    - Trip to moon, 8[81-88] (Othertype 5 1)
    - Moon Rocket Bus, 12 [89-100] (Othertype 7 1)
    - Moon Rocket Bus, 15 [101-115] (Othertype 7 1)
- Symphony No. 2, "Africa"
  - North, Alex. Manuscripts and parts. Extra pieces. Main theme. (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - North, Alex. Parts. Original onions and parts. (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 42, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 43, Folder unknown container)
  - North, Alex. Parts. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - North, Alex. Parts. Road parts. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - North, Alex. Parts. Road parts. (Box 45, Folder unknown container)
- Symphony to a New Continent
  - North, Alex. (94 unnumbered pages) [Holograph, in pencil, of musical sketch] (Box 12, Folder 49)